日本語字幕仕上げ：光川  光荣字幕组（www.koeigame.cn）
I need to concentrate. My chance will come soon.
集中切らすな  俺必ず
またどこかでチャンスは来る
Sera!
世良！
There it is! A nice pass.
来た！　ナイスパス
This is my chance!
このワンチャンス
I'll make it count!
ここで俺が絶対に決める！
Here goes!
行けっ！
Sera...
あ…　世良
United we stand,Fly a flag 風を受け止めて
United we stand, Fly a flag!
kaze o uketomete
風を受け止めて
Let the wind blow through you
United we stand,Fly a flag たなびけ勝利のflag
United we stand, Fly a flag!
tanabike shouri no flag
たなびけ勝利の flag
Let the victory flag trail in the wind
遥かなゴールを信じて 走り続けていて
haruka na gooru o shinjite
遥かなゴールを信じて
Believe in the goal that lies in wait and keep running
hashiri tsuzuketeke
走り続けてけ
日々夢紡ぐ者達へ 降り注げ光よ
hibi yume tsumugu monotachi e furisosoge hikari yo
日々夢紡ぐ者達へ降り注げ光よ
Let light pour down upon the weaver of dreams
汗は裏切らないって 唇噛み締め
ase wa uragiranaitte kuchibiru kamishime
汗は裏切らないって唇噛み締め
Your sweat won't betray you, so bite down on your lips
何度も立ち上がり 大地を駆け抜ける
nandomo tachiagari daichi o kakenukeru
何度も立ち上がり大地を駆け抜ける
And stand back up again and again as you dash across the earth
夢に終わりはないって 目を輝かせ
yume ni owari wa naitte me o kagayakase
Our dreams never end, so keep on shining
Let's start now GIANT KILLING!
for the right
For the right! Hold on tight!
hold on tight
my story…
My story...
forever
Forever...
Sakai!
さかい堺！
Take up the same position and maintain the pressure.
同じポジションに入って
前線でキプしろ
世良 世良 世良 世良…
Oh, really?
ねんざあ　ホント？
Sera only has a slight sprain? That's a relief.
軽い捻挫か　世良
そいつはよかった
Yeah, but he'll have to rest for a week.
うん…　まあ　でも
１週間は無理しないでほしいわね
He's young though, so he'll recover quickly.
若いから治り早いだろうけど
A week, huh?
１週間か
Our match against Shimizu yesterday ended all square.
昨日の清水戦も引き分けてしまったし
We needed to keep the momentum going, but ended up losing a forward instead.
勢いに乗りたいところで　フォワドが１枚減るのは
結構きついですね
It's going to be hard.
Right, Coach?
ねえ　監督くん
Yeah.
Oh man, I didn't get any of our players.
なんだぁ
ウチの選手出なかったよ
What are you doing?
もう　何やってんのよ！
Are there manager cards in these, too?
これって監督のカド　入ってんの？
How would I know?! And we're discussing something serious right now!
知らないわよ！
今　まじめに話してんでしょ？
Why are you always like this?!
何で達海さんは　いつも　そんな…
Relax, it's alright.
いいじゃん　いいじゃん
What's important is that Sera's injury isn't serious.
世良のケガが軽かっただけでさ
シズン　まだまだ続くんだ
The season's just started.
We mustn't panic just because of this.
こんぐらいであたふたしてられっかよ
So how's Sera doing?
で　世良はどうしてるんです？
He's usually very loud,
うん？　いつもは　ギャギャ騒がしいくせにね
but he seems to be dejected right now.
あの子にしちゃ珍しく　しょげてたわよ
I'm such an idiot. What am I doing?
あ　俺のバカ
何やってんだよ
I should be doing my best to hold on to my first-team status,
死ぬ気でレギュラ争いしなきゃいけない時に
but I screwed myself up instead.
自分から脱落するとは…
Oh man, this is too much.
ああ　あんまりだ…
Even God is telling me that ETU's main forward should be Natsu.
神様も言ってんだＥＴＵのフォワドはナツさんだって
If I were really a top player,
本当に大成する選手だったら
I wouldn't have injured myself right when my chance came.
チャンスもらっといてこんなつまんないケガはしない
I guess that's all I've got.
結局
この程度の器なんだ…　俺は
You'll be putting on weight if you keep eating greasy stuff.
そんな油っぽいもん食ってっと脂肪がついて体が重くなるぞ
S-Sakai...
さ…　堺さん
But whatever, that's just what I need.
まあ　俺にとっちゃ好都合だけどよ
With you out of the picture, I'll finally get a chance to be in the starting line-up.
お前がいなきゃ試合に出られやすいし
Eat more and get fatter. Be injured longer.
もっと食って　太れ　太れ
ケガも長引け
He doesn't mince his words, as usual.
相変わらずきつい言い方すんなぁ
Oh, are you about to head home, Sakai?
あれ？　堺さん今から帰りスか？
What, is there a problem with that?
なんだよ　悪いかよ！
いや…　俺
Uh no, it's just that everybody's gone when I finished my medical examination.
精密検査から帰ってきたらみんな　もう　いなかったから
…っつうかなんで怒るんスか？
Wait, why are you so angry?
I was getting a preventative massage.
入念にマッサジしてもらってたんだよ
It can't be helped. I'm already 31.
しかたねえだろ俺　もう３１なんだからよ
コンディション維持するだけで大変なんだよ
It's tough enough for me just to maintain my physical condition.
And here you are eating potato chips!
なのに！
お前はポテトチップ食ってるし
Kuroda and Sugie were also talking about eating ramen! Stop screwing around!
黒田と杉江は　ラメン食ったとか言うしよ
ふざけんな！
Geez... Just because you're young,
ったくよ
若いからって調子に乗って
you get carried away and ignore your diet.
食事とか気を付けねえから
That's why you get injured when it matters.
大事なとこでケガとかすんだよ
I can't even rebuke the argument.
あ…　返す言葉もない
Just remain the way you are.
はっ！　腐ってろ　腐ってろ
If I play, I'll score your share of the goals too.
俺が出たら
お前の分まで　ゴル決めてきてやるよ
Damn!
クッソ
But still,
まあ　でもよ…
I would have taken that shot, too.
あの場面はシュトに行くよな
I'll bet Matsu yelled at you.
お前松さんに怒られてたろ
That time, Tsubaki was unmarked behind you.
つばきあの時　椿が後ろでフリだったってよ
Instead, you forced a shot and hurt yourself.
それを無理に打ちに行ってケガした
But you know you had to.
でもよ
打ちに行くよな
You didn't consider the possibility of getting hurt.
ケガするなんて考えずによ
フォワドだもんなあ…
We're forwards after all.
Forwards are like that.
そういう人種なんだよなフォワドってよ
We put goal-scoring above everything else.
何より自分のゴルが欲しいんだ
ヘン　勘違いすんなよ　世良
Don't get me wrong me, Sera.
I'm only sympathizing you,
俺は同情してやってるだけだぜ
since I can understand the feelings of a fellow forward.
フォワドのヤツの気持ちは分かるってだけだ
I might be past my prime.
俺はピクを過ぎたかもしれない
I'm neither as strong as Natsuki nor as fast as you,
夏木の勝負強さも　お前のスピドも
俺はもう持ってない
but I don't think I'm inferior compared to the both of you.
でも　俺はお前たちに劣ってるとは思わねえ
負けるつもりはさらさらないぜ
I have no intention of giving up.
So how about you, Sera?
お前はどうなんだよ？　世良え？
Have you've already admitted defeat to Natsuki?
もう夏木に負けたつもりか？あ…
If that's the case, it's over for you.
だとしたらお前は
そこ止まりだ
It's over, the end.
終わりだ　終わり
You know, the ball...
ボルってのはな　世良
...will always roll towards the person who never gives up.
しぶとく　あきらめないヤツの前に必ず転がってくるもんなんだよ
That's what I think.
これ　俺の持論
I won't give up either!
俺も負けねえっス！
いいって　ポテトチップ食えって
It's fine, just continue eating your chips.
I won't!
アハッ　食わないっス！
Once in a while is fine.
いいじゃん　食えよ
No, enough is enough!
嫌っス！　もうやめたっス
Don't hold back.
遠慮すんな
いらないっス！
I don't want 'em. You can have 'em instead.
East Tokyo United…
6th League Match
ETU vs Urawa Red Stars
Alright, let's go!
おし　行くぜ！
Unfortunately, I'm not starting, but at least I made the bench.
スタメンじゃねえのは残念だけど
久々のベンチ入りだ
I might even get some playing time!
こりゃ出番があるかもな
I'm sorry, Hotta.
すいません　堀田さん
Look where you're going, Natsuki.
ま…　前見ようぜ夏木
But still, you're way too excited.
しかし
気合い入れすぎだろ お前
You're already drenched from doing warm-ups.
何で既に汗だくなんだよ？
ま　そりゃあ気合いも入りますよ
Well, I have to.
The cheers from the Urawa fans make it look like they're the hosts instead.
ホムとは思えないほどのアウェ浦和の大声援
The tension of a goal-less game...
ゼロ　ゼロの　拮抗した試合展開
And on the bench is a lonely samurai who just returned from injury.
そして　ベンチにはケガから復帰した　一匹の侍
Who?
誰のこと？
It's the perfect stage for me to emerge as the hero.
まさに俺がヒロになるには格好の舞台
The perfect stage!
格好の舞台ですよ！
Don't try to make the manager hear that.
監督に聞こえるように言うなよ
Damn, Urawa. They started off weakly.
チキショめ　浦和
立ち上がり悪かったくせによ
They've adjusted well...
しっかり修正してきましたねうん
Yeah, their players are linking up well.
選手同士がよく声掛け合ってる
I wonder if we can make them panic again.
もう一回バタつかせられるかな？
It's a bit early, but I guess now's the time.
ちょっと早いけど
動くなら今か
Kaneyan, call Natsuki.
カネやん
夏木呼んで
It doesn't feel good when you're not playing.
うう…　自分が出てない試合って　気持ちが悪い
I want us to win, but not by a huge margin.
勝ってほしいけど　ボロ勝ちは嫌だし
I don't want us to lose either.
負けんのは嫌だし…
I shouldn't have gotten myself injured.
やっぱり　ケガなんてするもんじゃねえ
Hey, look!
おい　あれ！
He's here!
来た！
We've waited a long time for this!
随分待ったぞ　コラ！
Good job, Sakai.
お疲れっス　堺さん
Just leave everything to me. Everything!
あとは俺にどんと任して！
どんと！
I'm off then, manager!
行ってきますよ　監督
I'll show you my manliness!
男を上げてきますから　俺！
Shut up and go already.
うっさいな
早く行けって
これだ…
This is it...
I've waited eight months for this moment.
この瞬間を俺は８か月　待ってたんだ
うっしゃ！　おい　浦和！
Oh yeah! Come on, Urawa! I'll take you on!
俺が相手だ！
Bring it!
かかってこいや！
I-Is he crying?
な…　泣いてねえか？　こいつ
Why can't he be more normal?
普通にできないの？　あいつ
夏木 夏木 夏木
Thank you, fans...
ありがとう　サポタ
for waiting for me after I took a shot in a strange posture
変な体勢でシュトを打って
and landed awkwardly, resulting in an eight month layoff.
変な着地して
８か月も棒に振った俺を待っててくれて
ありがとう　後藤さん
Thank you, Mr. Goto, for not giving up on me.
俺を切らないでいてくれて
Thank you, Doc, my wife and my daughter, for supporting me.
ありがとう　先生…
嫁…
娘
こんな俺を支えててくれて
Thank you, manager, for giving me a chance.
ありがとう　監督
俺にチャンスをくれて
I'll...
俺は
show them what I can do on the pitch!
１人の男として
必ず　このピッチで結果を！
Counter!
カウンタ！
Huh?
ドリ！
Dori!
よっしゃ！　ハハハハ！
あっ　クソ！
Damn!
あぁ　やられた
Damn, they caught us unaware.
あ…　あれ？俺が出た途端？
Huh? The moment I got in?
That's right.
そうだった…
It's usually like this.
そうだったじゃねえか
This is the stage for a real showdown, where you can't let your guard down.
ここは一瞬たりとも気を抜けない
真剣勝負の舞台
俺が８か月求めてたのは
This is the world I've been dreaming of for the past eight months.
そういう世界じゃねえか！
They will pile on the pressure now that they've got a goal.
１点取って向こうは引いてくるぞ！
前がかりに行かなきゃ点取れねえぞ！
If we don't push forward, we can't score!
That goal came from your side, Akasaki! Watch out for their counters!
お前んとこで決められたんだろうが　バカサキ！
カウンタの警戒もしろよ！
Stop arguing!
くだらない言い合いするなディフェンスライン　もう少し上げろ！
Push the defense line up a lil' more.
Hmm... It'll be bad if we continue on like this...
うん…こうなると困ったねぇ
ナイスカバ　椿！
Nice cover, Tsubaki.
Damn!
クッソ！　このままじゃ　向こうのペスで　ズルズルいきかねませんね
We'll be playing into their momentum at this rate.
They're closing down so fast that it's hard to carry the ball forward.
チェック早くてボルが前に運べねえ
Hey, I'm free!
タンさん　オライ！
よし　ナツさんもう１回　サイドから組み立て…
Alright, Natsu, let's set it up from the side.
夏木！！
Natsuki!
He scored!
決めた！
How was that?!
どうだ！　どうだ！
Natsuki Yotaro! The miraculous comeback kid!
夏木陽太郎！奇跡の　大復活弾！
やった！
Yes!
That was an amazing shot by Natsuki!
スゲエの打ちやがったな夏木のヤツ
He's always so refined when he shoots!
決める時だけは派手ですからね　あいつ
Natsu's goals always look like a fluke.
ホント　いっつも　まぐれっぽいよねナッツのゴルって
ま いいか悪いかは別としてそれがあいつらしさでもあるし
Well, either way, that's how he is.
It really feels like he's back. Our No.11...
本当に戻ってきたって感じがするよな
ウチの１１番が
I did it. I scored!
やった…　やったぜ
This is amazing.
最高だ…
My little girl fell asleep, but it's still amazing!
娘　寝ちゃってるけど　最高だ！
My season starts right now!
ここからだ　俺のシズンは
I'll pile up the goals and make up for last year!
ドッカドッカ　ゴル決めまくって去年の借りを倍返ししてやる
Alright! Let's do this, guys!
よし　行くぞ　お前ら！
Since when did you take the lead, Natsuki? Quit getting ahead of yourself.
何　仕切ってんだよ　夏木　調子乗んじゃねえよ！
I'm heading back to put some ice on.
裏で　アイシングしてくるわ風邪とか　こじらせらんねえし
Otherwise, I might catch a cold.
Uh, sure.
あ…　ウス
Damn, I mustn't lose to him!
チッ…　負けてられっか
So what? So what?
あんなのが何だってんだよ　あんなのが
He scored right after getting on?!
いきなり結果出すとは！
You know, the ball...
ボルってのはな　世良
will always roll towards the person who never gives up.
しぶとく　あきらめないヤツの前に必ず転がってくるもんなんだよ
That's right.
そうだ…今だけだからな　ナツさん
It's only for now, Natsu.
I'm just letting you catch up a lil'.
今は出遅れた分のハンディをくれてやってるだけだ
The real battle starts when I'm back in training!
本当の勝負は俺のケガが治った時だ
うおおっ！　早く治れ　お前！
Heal already, you jerk! I mean, me!
お前っつうか　俺！
Natsuki changed the game there.
決定的な仕事をしたわね　夏木
He scored when it mattered the most.
一番　取ってほしい時間に決めてくれた
At this point in time, the No.1 forward is unquestionably Natsuki.
現時点での　ナンバワンフォワドは夏木で決まりってところね
Sakai, Sera, and Natsuki.
堺と　世良と　夏木
It looks like the battle for the forward position is firing up now.
ここに来て　フォワドのポジション争いが活性化しそうね
Ever since the Nagoya game, ETU have been in good form.
名古屋戦以降好調続きのＥＴＵ
Plus, Natsuki's comeback will foreshadow even greater things.
夏木の復帰がそれに拍車をかける
Will this be a fair assumption, Coach?
そう見ていいのかしらね？監督さん
惜しい
A draw?
ドロかよ！惜しい！
Dammit!
Argh, they were so close!
ぐあ！もうちょっとだったのに！
That makes it 5 games without loss.
ここ５試合　負け無し！
なあ　ＥＴＵは大したもんだろ？
ETU's pretty good. Right, Yoshi, Shinkichi?
よしちゃん！　伸吉！
There are more now...
増えてる…
We weren't defeated by Urawa, who we've lost to for three straight years.
ここ３年　連敗しまくってた浦和相手に
負けなかった
Maybe... we've really gotten better.
なんかうまくなってんのかもな　俺たち
Yo.
よう　派手な復帰戦になったなハッハ
That was a great comeback game.
そうスか？　てれるなぁ
You think so? You're making me blush.
Hey, don't get cocky!
コラ！　調子に乗んなよ
Hey, you two!
おい　お前ら！　俺たちは勝ったわけじゃねえんだぞ はしゃいで　どうすんだ
It's not like we've won.
What's there to fool around?
Understood!
ウス！
Sorry!
すんません
That said though, this may indeed prove that the team's improving.
ま　これもチムが勢いに乗れてる証拠かもな
夏木　ナイスゴル！
Nice goal, Natsuki!
You did well, let's win the next one!
よくやった！　次は勝とうぜ！
どうしたの　達海さん？
What's wrong, Tatsumi?
The team is doing well, so you should be happy too.
チムがいい調子なんだから監督もシャキッとしてよね
Well, let's go.
さ　行きましょ
Doing well, huh?
いい調子ねえ…
You've got find the way to believe
carry on and carry on
Carry on and carry on
Till you can see tomorrow
I'll say “never look back”
I'll say 「never look back」
oikaze o matte
追い風を待って
Wait for the tailwind
sou chance o nogasunara
そう chance を逃すなら
And if you missed the chance
そうchanceをのがすなら
自分が風になれ no fears no tears
jibun ga kaze ni nare
自分が風になれ
Become the wind yourself
no tears,Yes Let it go！
No fears! No tears! Yes! Let it go!
Get tough! Get tough!
Get tough！(Stay gold！)
Stay gold!
Get tough！(We'll go！)
We'll go!
限界追い越せ
genkai oikose yuke
限界追い越せ行け
Surpass your limits and go!
行け キツイほど
kitsui hodo heart in red
キツイほど　heart in red
The harder it is the redder your heart will be!
heart in red
Go on! Go on!
Go on！(Stay cool！）
Stay cool!
Go on！(We'll go！)
We'll go!
asu wa mienai dakara
あすは見えないだから
Because we can't see into the future
あすは見えない だから
It's time to go
It's time to go yamerarenai
It's time to go やめられない
So it's time to go. We can't quit!
やめられない
Get tough!
Get tough！Get tough！ Get tough！
Get tough！(Stay gold！)
Get tough! Get tough!
Stay gold!
Get tough！(We'll go！)
We'll go!
共に乗り越えて 行け
tomo ni norikoete yuke
共に乗り越えて行け
Let's get through it together
見えるか It's daybreak there
mieruka It's daybreak there
Can you see that it's daybreak there?
Go on! Go on!
Go on！(Stay cool！) Go on！(We'll go！)
Stay cool!
We'll go!
yosoku dekinai dakara
予測できないだから
The future is unpredictable
It's time to go
It's time to go tomerarenai
It's time to go 止められない
So it's time to go. We can't stop!
止められない
I'm not saying that a draw is bad, but...
Starting tomorrow, we'll be having an intense training programme for the Osaka match.
What? That's all?